https://www.mpi.org/about/privacy

Search
Meeting Professionals International Data Privacy PolicyIntroductionAt MPI we recognize the importance of securing and protecting all data and the privacy of certain basic personally identifiable data, such as contact information, demographic information and payment processing information. We do not collect data from
individuals unless provided to us voluntarily and knowingly and with access to update and change the data at will. We have adopted this Data Privacy Policy to guide how we and our affiliates (i.e. account holders, members, vendors, staff, chapter
leadership) use such information. This policy meets the requirements of GDPR, PIPEDA, and the FTC Act.PurposeThe purpose of this Policy is to balance our legitimate business requirements in collecting and using information with the reasonable expectation of privacy and security which may be held by those providing such information.Data CollectionIt is necessary for us to collect and store information to provide requested member and customer communication and related services and for billing purposes. Many state and federal laws require the collection and retention of some or all of such information
for a determinate period of time. At MPI we collect data via four methods: membership registration, event activities, vendor partnerships, and purchases.Membership and Account Holder InformationWe collect key information from our members to provide valuable member services and for operational effectiveness. Members provide data directly when creating an MPI account and can update preferences via the web portal. We collect additional data upon
engagement with our website using cookie based technology.We specifically collect these types of data:Name and contact data. We collect your first and last name, phone number, address, email address, and other related data.Demographic data. We collect data about you such as your gender, chapter membership, and country.Payment data. We collect data necessary to process your payment if you make purchases (such as a credit card number).Credentials. We collect passwords, password hints, and similar security information used for authentication of accounts.Session Tracking. At times we record user sessions on our website to identify how we can provide better features and services.Contact Logs. Any communication or contact with MPI members is tracked in contact logs as well as additional engagement data (clock hours, conference attendance, purchases, etc.).Event InformationAt times, MPI receives and collects personal information through informal methods such as business cards, sign up lists, and event registration. In these cases, we only use this information to provide member services and stated purposes outlined upon
collection. Marketing, advertisements, and solicitations will not be sent unless explicitly outlined and agreed to in this data privacy statement.Vendor PartnershipsWe partner with third-party vendors who provide additional services such as learning management systems, speaker contracting, surveys, and job boards. These partners may maintain member data specific to their provided service. All vendors are vetted to
ensure they have proper data privacy and security procedures.For the complete list of MPI's third-party partners contact dataprivacy@mpi.org.Purchased DataWe purchase data from vetted vendors. To ensure above board practices, we vet each vendor to ensure compliant data collection, security, and use policies and processes. All purchased data collection and use will follow the guidelines stated in this policy
and the terms specified by the vendor.Data Privacy OptionsYou have choices about the data we collect. When you are asked to provide personal data, you may opt out. However, please note certain contact information is required for MPI membership.To update your data or change preferences simply navigate to the "Account Settings" section of the MPI website.To request anonymization or deletion of your data, please fill out this form. MPI will ensure the request is fulfilled within 30 days excluding the extent MPI is
required by law to retain some or all the member data.SecurityThe security of data is very important to us and we are committed to protecting the information we collect. We collect information only in a manner deemed reasonably necessary to serve our legitimate business purposes and comply with our legal obligations.
We use commercially reasonable efforts to make our collection of information consistent with all applicable laws and regulations. We exercise care in providing secure transmission and storage of information. Unfortunately, no data transmission or
storage is 100% secure. We cannot warrant that all data we transmit, store and collect will be completely secure. We take commercially reasonable efforts to create and maintain firewalls, restricted access and secure socket layers, and other appropriate
safeguards to ensure that, to the extent we control information, it is used only as authorized by us and consistent with this Policy, and that information is not improperly altered or destroyed. In addition, within MPI we limit data access to only
what is required for a role to complete their responsibilities. Our privacy protection practices help us maintain accurate, timely, complete and relevant information for our business purposes. Our communication system, software and database practices
have been designed to aid us in supporting authenticity, integrity and confidentiality.Data Breach PolicyWe want to ensure that your identity and data stays secure; therefore, if an incident does occur, and for incidents that occur at our third-party vendors, we will promptly inform affected individuals as may be required by law or our policies.Data UseWe may use your information to offer goods and services we believe will be of value to members on behalf of MPI, our affiliates and our partners. We may use contact data to inquire or survey about conference experiences, chapter engagement, education
opportunities or general membership satisfaction. We may also create and use aggregate information that is not personally identifiable to understand more about the common profiles and interests of our members and website visitors.Special Offers and Promotion OptionsIt is MPI's policy to only communicate with members via channels that have been informed and accepted via this policy and on the online preference page. Members, account holders, and visitors are given the opportunity to alter communication preferences
via the membership account portal.All communications will provide the opportunity to opt-out of future similar communications.Vendor PartnersMPI shares personal data with vendors working on our behalf for the purposes described in this statement. For example, vendors securing our systems and services may need access to personal data to provide those functions. In such cases, these companies
must abide by the MPI Data Privacy Policy and are contractually prohibited from using personal data they obtain for any other purpose.Third-Party OffersMembers can opt in for a wider range of services and products through advertising and marketing. Our partners are subject to MPI's data policy guidelines and members will only receive the information for which explicit permission has been granted.Event Coordination and Third-Party OffersIndividuals may be required to agree to MPI's data privacy policy when registering for MPI events. Third-parties may be given event attendee information for event coordination and offers related to the event.CookiesOur website utilizes "cookie" technology. "Cookies" are encrypted strings of text that a Web site stores on a user's computer. Our Web site uses cookies throughout the online process to maximize website performance. In addition, cookies are used to:Measure usage of various pages on our website to help us make our information more pertinent to your needs and easy for you to access;Provide functionality such as online registration and other functionality that we believe would be of interest and value to you; andServe advertisements and business opportunities to users, and allow select partners of MPI, to serve online advertisements through remarketing and programmatic channels also known as behavioral advertising.The two types of cookies that we use are referred to as "session" cookies and "persistent" cookies. Session cookies are temporary and are automatically deleted once you leave our website. Persistent cookies remain on your computer hard drive until you
delete them. We do not use cookies to gather any personally identifiable information about you apart from what you voluntarily provide us in your dealings with us. Our cookies do not corrupt or damage your computer, programs or computer files.Upon arrival to www.mpi.org, a cookie policy notification and acceptance will be presented. Website users may set browser preferences to block cookies (consult browser provider for specific instructions or choose to allow MPI to use cookies on your machine
by accepting cookie policy or continuing to use the website.) Disabling cookies will adversely affect your ability to perform certain transactions, use certain functionality, and access certain content on our website.Compliance with LawWe may disclose Member Information to law enforcement agencies, or may be required to disclose it during the discovery process in litigation, pursuant to a court order, or in compliance with any applicable law, regulation, rule or ordinance.Chapters/Affiliated Sites/LinksMPI provides members with various URL links that may be beneficial or of interest to our membership. Many of these sites are owned and operated by independent companies and organizations that are neither owned nor controlled by MPI. Each Chapter, URL
or link may collect information and use such information for its own purposes. MPI does not control the use or access of such information collected by these sites. MPI is not responsible in any manner for damage or loss caused or alleged to be caused
by or in connection with the use of or reliance on any content, advertising, services, products or other material on or available from such sites.Questions or CommentsAny questions or comments that relate to the MPI Privacy Protection Policy may be directed to us at MPI, Data Privacy Executive 2711 Lyndon B. Johnson Freeway, Suite 600, Dallas, TX, 75234-7349, and dataprivacy@mpi.orgCopyright and Trademark NoticesAll contents of this website are protected by United States and International Copyright and Trademark law. Any unauthorized use is strictly prohibited and may subject a violator to civil and criminal penalties. All rights reserved.Privacy Protection Policy ChangesIn the future, we may need to change this Policy. MPI reserves the right to modify this Data Privacy Policy at any time without prior notice. All changes will be included on this Website so that you will always know what information we gather, how we
might use that information and whether we will disclose it to anyone. This Policy was last updated on April 20, 2018.
Tips & Advice
Dear Virtual Events: Don’t Forget Your #EventProfs!
The Independent Planners Collective
MPI Foundation
Need a scholarship?
The MPI Foundation can help
